# **Anurag Kumar Singh**

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER · <a href="http://anurag27k.github.io/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/anurag27k/</a> anurag27k@gmail.com · +91 9445682075

#### **SUMMARY**

Anurag is a result oriented and senior product designer with 6+ years of expertise spanning various sectors, including Demand supply management, Healthcare, ERP and Government permitting and licensing. Demonstrated proficiency in design and coding, with a track record of handling complex projects with success. Integrates technical skills with a strong aesthetic sense. He has led teams to harness success and create a culture of constant improvement while contributing to the design community. He has a record of driving projects from 0 to 1 while working on multiple work streams parallely. He is a proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

#### **SKILLS**

### Core Skills:

UX Design & Research · UI Design · Interaction Design · Web Development · Testing & Evaluation · User Centered Design · Data Visualization · Service Design · Accessibility · Mixed media · Augmented Reality · Virtual Reality · Graphic Design · Color Theory · Typography · Layout Design

#### Soft/business Skills:

Leadership and Team Management · Design Strategy and Conceptualization · Creative Direction Project Management Skills · Problem-Solving and Critical Thinking · Strategic Thinking · Presentation Skills · Continuous Learning and Adaptability · Product Vision Definition · Effective Communication · Complex Problem Solving · Planned and Systematic Execution

#### **EDUCATION**

## IDC School of Design, IIT Bombay

## NIT Tiruchirappalli

Master of Design (Interaction Design)

B.Tech (Computer Science & Engineering)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Intuit, Bengaluru** Senior Product Designer Jun 2024 - Present

- Led multiple work streams inside the VEP team (Virtual Expert Platform) involving demand forecasting, capacity planning, allocation and ramp/supply procurement.
- As a platform team, which worked across verticals, I worked in influencing strategy and tech decisions, and AI inclusion, to drive teams towards a more cohesive system where the manual process and tribal knowledge of users is eliminated and users (or planners) can make confident decisions.
- Led team of 3 designers in making their design and decision making processes stronger. Also mentored them from time to time to uplift them professionally making them capable for industry.

## Oracle Tech Hub, Bengaluru

Aug 2022 - Jun 2024

User Experience Designer

- Led various commercial projects on government and citizen facing applications which help in permitting, licensing, planning and code enforcement.
- Built synergies with cross-functional teams, of PM, developers and designers, across geographies to develop processes which reduced effort for efficient, timely and scalable results.
- Worked upon strategies to incorporate Al in future vision projects while handling projects independently and provided leadership and guidance to junior designers, fostering their professional growth and development.

May 2021 - Jul 2021

Interaction Designer

- Contributed innovative ideas and solutions to address on a project which involved creating a roadmap planning and employee management application which would effectively reduce the errors while project estimations.
- Conducted user research, usability testing, and analysis to inform the design process and enhance the user experience.
- Created wireframes, prototypes, and user flows to visualize and iterate on design solutions, prioritizing usability and accessibility.

#### **Cerner Corporation**

Apr 2020 - Aug 2020

User Experience Designer

- Enabled physicians to dismiss/delete the Al proposed opportunities, a proposed documentation opportunity or clinical validation notification, presented by the NLP Engine of the system.
- Reduced the clicks by 33% while keeping actions least intrusive for the physician.
- Interfaced directly with clients to understand their design requirements, gather feedback, and address any concerns or revisions promptly.

## People10 Technologies Inc.

May 2018 - Jun 2019

User Interface/Experience Designer

- Single handedly worked on developing an application for the Bomb squad to record and report details of the suspect package.
- Developed visually appealing and on-brand designs across various mediums including web, mobile, and print. There were 3 parts in here namely collaborator app, marketing website and branding.

**Philips Healthcare** Jun 2016 - May 2018

UX Designer and Engineer

- I had the opportunity to work in 2 teams over here. In my first team I worked in the Health watch team where I contributed innovative ideas and solutions to address complex design challenges while handling creation of REST Microservices and their APIs for onboarding experiences.
- In my second team, I created wireframes, prototypes, and user flows to visualize while working on MRI
  dashboards which demanded adaptability and flexibility in widgets. I was also involved in development
  of this application using front end technologies like AngularJS, HTML, CSS

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Exploration of inter-marker interactions in Tangible AR

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3562939.3565642

VRST '22: Proceedings of the 28th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology

- In this paper we explore multiple inter-marker interactions in the tangible AR space along with their use cases. We developed prototypes that demonstrate primarily five inter-marker interactions.

#### Grapho: Bringing line chart accessibility to the visually impaired

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3570211.3570213

IndiaHCI '22: Proceedings of the 13th Indian Conference on Human-Computer Interaction

- In this paper we propose Grapho, a graph visualization physical tool that allows a visually-impaired person to perceive, create and modify a line chart.

#### LEISURE

Badminton · Boardgames · Guitar · Playstation · Old music classics · Fiction · Al creations · Sketching · Concerts